(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-10T02:08:58.698997",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
月夜のセレナーデ
Moonlit serenade...
白い薔薇は誰を想う
Who is the white rose thinking of?
その身を震わせて
Trembling in body,
愛を歌うの
it sings of love.
零れ落ちた花びらが
Fallen petals
寂しさの跡を隠した
hid the traces of loneliness.
ねえ早く迎えに来て
Come and welcome me soon,
最後のひたひらが落ちるその前に
before the very last petal falls.
今宵はどんな華とも群れないの
Tonight, I won't flock with any other flower;
あなただけを待っている
I'm only waiting for you.
あなたと ならこの体が 壊されたって もう構わない
With you, even if this body were broken,
壊されたって もう構わない
I wouldn't care anymore.
棘に触れたら傷つくわ
Touching the thorns will hurt you.
その覚悟がない なら
If you don't have that resolve,
いっそそこから消えてよ
then just disappear from there.
重く閉ざした そう secret garden
Heavily closed... yes, a secret garden.
夜風はリゾールト
Night wind is resolute,
白い薔薇は覚醒する
and the white rose awakens.
背中押されるように
As if pushed from behind,
扉開いた
the door opened.
ただ独りで枯れてゆく の？
Are you just going to wither away all alone?
待ってる だけじゃいられない
I can't just sit and wait anymore.
衝動の赴くまま
Surrendering to the urge,
茨の道を裸足で駆け抜けてく
I run barefoot through the path of briars.
凛と咲き誇る華でありたい
I want to be a flower blooming proudly.
あなただけを求めて
Seeking only you,
逢いにゆく の
I'm going to meet you.
どんな遠く離れていても見つけ出せる
No matter how far apart we are, I can find you.
暗い世界も怖くない
Even a dark world isn't scary
あなたを感じるから
because I feel you.
全て失ったっていい
It's okay to lose everything;
二度と戻らない そう secret garden
we'll never return... yes, a secret garden.
お姫様にしてよ！
Make me your princess!
ずっと将来の夢は
My dream for the future is always...
王子の横のキラキラgirl
to be a glittering girl by the prince's side!
ドレスを着て舞踏会
Wearing a dress to the ball,
(超可愛い！)
(Super cute!)
大人になれば勝手になれるものだと思ってた
I used to think growing up just happens naturally.
あれあれ？
Huh? Huh?
気付けば
Before I knew it...
武闘派のキュート社会人
I'm a militant, cute working adult!
「嘘でしょ！？」
"You've gotta be kidding!"
優雅なモーニンぐは
An elegant morning...
この世界になくて
doesn't exist in this world!
スヌーズは騒がしい
The snooze alarm is so noisy,
でも でも
even so...
魔法使いは見てるもん！
magicians are watching over me!
お姫様にしてよ！
Make me your princess!
ほら白馬乗って渋谷を駆け巡ろうよ
Let's ride a white horse and dash around Shibuya!
毒林檎かじって
Take a bite of a poisoned apple...
眠りにつこう
and drift off to sleep.
ガラスの靴は片方だけ
Leave just one glass slipper behind
階段に残してあげる
on the stairs.
全員ヒロイン=LOVE!
We are all heroines = LOVE!
頑張ってる私
Working hard,
仮眠取りたいとこだけど
I just want to take a nap,
ランチはクリームのパスタ
but lunch is cream pasta!
(超可愛い！)
(Super cute!)
小鳥さんと歌って突然くるくる回って
Singing with little birds, suddenly spinning around—
世界はいつでも私の全て見守る
the world always watches over my everything!
可愛い香水は
Cute perfume...
職場に似合わないし
doesn't suit the workplace,
満員の電車には Ah ああ
and the packed train is... Ah...
私の世界は狭すぎる！
My world is just too cramped!
お姫様になって
Become a princess,
ふかふかのベッド転がり愛を語ろう
lying on a fluffy bed, let's talk about love.
深く眠ったら
Once you fall fast asleep,
優しいキスを
give me a gentle kiss.
ちょっと待ってよ仕事のこと今ここで話さないでよ
Hold on, don't talk about work right now!
戦うヒロイン=LOVE!
Fighting heroines = LOVE!
守ってもらってばかりは嫌だし強くて甘いの
Protecting me is boring, I want someone strong yet sweet—
令和のプリンセスよ
the princess of the Reiwa era!
とは言えこのシーンは
That being said, this scene...
君からグッと近づいてきてささやきでしょ！？
must be you coming in close to hit on me, right?!
よーいスタート！
Good start!
お姫様にしてよ！
Make me your princess!
ほら白馬乗って渋谷を駆け巡ろうよ
Let's ride a white horse and dash around Shibuya!
毒林檎かじって
Take a bite of a poisoned apple
眠りにつけばすぐに目を覚まして
and the moment you fall asleep, wake up immediately—
区役所行ってウェディング！
let's go to the ward office for a wedding!
全員ヒロイン=LOVE!
All-member heroine = LOVE!
ということで、そろそろ自己紹介しましょう！
And that concludes our self-introductions!
みなさんこんこんきつねー！白上フブキでーす！
Hello everyone, I'm Fubuki Shirakami, the Konkon Kitsune with white fox hair!
そして！ホロライブの清純担当、みんなのアイドル夏色まつりです！
And I'm Matsuri Natsuri, the idol of Hololive's 1st generation!
はいみなさんアロハ～！ホロライブの癒やし系ハーフエルフ、アキ・ローゼンタールでーす！
Hello everyone, I'm Aki Rosenthal from Hololive's 1st generation!
はいはーちゃまっちゃま！ワールドワイドの最強アイドルはーちゃまこと、赤井はーとでーす！
And I'm Haachama, the strongest idol in the universe with a red heart!
ということで本日ハッシュタグこちらですね！#ホロ1期生6周年 で、お願いしまーす！
And today's hashtag is #Hololive1stGen6thAnniversary!
おっと、なんと我々6周年でございますよ。
Well, remarkably, we are celebrating our 6th anniversary!
そうだね。
That's right.
今回6周年記念ライブのコンセプトがね、あの、みんなお姫様ということで、
The concept for our 6th anniversary live this time is that everyone is a princess, so
はい、ちょっとね、1曲目お姫様に仕立てようから歌わせていただきましたーー！
yes, for the first song, we had them sing it as princesses!
ちょっとね、今回なんとステージも一期生のライブ仕様になりました。
And you know, this time, even the stage has become a 1st generation live specification!
かわいい！すごい！
Cute! Amazing!
めちゃくちゃ豪華じゃない？
Isn't it super luxurious?
我々の後ろの城はみんなで建てた城やからね。そう、みんなのおかげでこの立派な城が建ちました。
The castle behind us is a castle we all built together. Yes, thanks to everyone, this splendid castle was built.
そうそう、で、上のほう、実は時計があるんですが、
That's right, and up at the top, there's actually a clock,
この時計、12時と見せかけて、実は23時59分で止まってる1分前。まあ、もう時計ないんだよね。
but this clock, pretending to be 12 o'clock, is actually stopped at 23:59, one minute before. Well, it doesn't tick, right?
そうなんです。で、そして今回ね、ステージ、今日来てくれてるみなさんのあのステージ、
That's right. And then, this time, the stage, for everyone who came today, that stage...
ステージ客席側が、なんと参加席まであるんだよ！みんな！みんな！参加席めちゃくちゃいる！
The audience side of the stage even has participation seats! Everyone! Everyone! There are so many participation seats!
いやーーすごい！すごい人ですよ、これ。
Man, amazing! That's an incredible crowd.
ねえ、みんなの声が聞こえる気がする。あ、みんなの声が。
Hey, I feel like I can hear everyone's voices. Ah, everyone's voices.
はい、ということで、ちょっと我々ね、6周年を迎えましたので、
Yes, with that said, since we've reached our 6th anniversary,
ちょっと改めて、なんかね、ちょっと振り返ってとか、
let's look back on things a bit anew, or...
これからね、我々斜めに、7年目に向けてでもいいんですけど、ちょっと、うん、ライブの意気込みでも全然いいですし、
From here on, we're heading towards our 7th year, or whatever, but yeah, enthusiasm for the live is totally fine too.
やばい。毎年周年きてるけど、もうそんなに経っているという。
It's crazy. Anniversaries come every year, but so much time has already passed.
本当、それだよ。え、じゃあちょっと、はあちゃまもある？
Seriously, that's right. Uh, well then, Haachama, do you have any?
なんで、はあちゃまからなの？
Why are you starting with Haachama?
いや、長いですね。7年目もね、にゃにゃにゃにゃ。
Well, it's been long. In the 7th year too, nya nya nya.
やっぱりアイドルらしく、あ、最近はアイドルとして頑張って行きたいと思います。え、ではあっきゅん！
As an idol, ah, lately I want to work hard as an idol. Uh, well then, Akkyun!
なに！早い！
What! So fast!
まぁまぁ、まさかやっぱ7年も続けてこられるっていうのをもう想像もしてなかったけど、
Well, I never imagined we'd be able to keep going for 7 years, but
でも今こうやってね、あの、みんなと一緒にまあライブできるのは、めちゃくちゃ嬉しい。
but now being able to do a live like this together with everyone is super happy.
うれしい！うれしい！
Happy! Happy!
まぁ、でも、まあ、アッテンに、ね、足をふみ入れたということで、7年目もラッキーセブンにあやかっていっぱい頑張れたいと思います。
Well, but, well, having stepped into Atten, right, in the 7th year too, I hope we can ride on lucky seven and do our best.
でもね、みんな王子様だからね。そうそうそうそう。そうだね。
But you know, everyone is a prince. That's right, right. That's right.
祭りも、あの、7年目に向けて頑張るのでね、あの、今年こそは王子様を見つけたいと思います。祭りのなかにいるかな？
Matsuri will also do her best toward the 7th year, so um, this year I definitely want to find a prince. Is one inside Matsuri?
やめてやめてください。
Stop, please stop.
かわいいだろ！かわいいからいいよ、かわいいから許せよ！
She's cute, right? It's fine because she's cute, forgive her because she's cute!
ええ、まあそして、まあ、ね、6年目、来年、いや頑張った、我々は本当に。
Uh, well and then, well, right, 6th year, next year, no, we worked hard, really.
でもね、7年目もね、ラッキーセブンで、なんかね、いいこといっぱいあるといいなと思っておりますね。
But you know, in the 7th year too, with lucky seven, I hope there will be lots of good things.
あと、これもこれもね、今日来てくれてるあの、王子様の皆様、王子様のね、皆様たちのね、おかげなので、
And also, this and that, thanks to all the princes who came today, thanks to everyone who is a prince,
王子様が、今日は王子、みんなが王子様か。
today the princes, everyone is a prince.
王子様だね。王子様、王子様、王子様。王子様歓迎だよ。王子もいるのか？王子様じゃないの？
A prince. Prince, prince, prince. Princes are welcome. Is there a prince too? Not a prince?
今日はね、来てくれてる王子様たちのために、我々ね、尽くしますので、王子様に仕え...
Today, for the princes who came, we will devote ourselves, serve the princes...
やめて！勘違いしないで！やめて！
Stop! Don't misunderstand! Stop!
さてじゃあ、次の曲に行きましょうかね。次なんだろう？
Well then, let's move on to the next song. What is next?
え？なんか、なんか動きがした？
Huh? Did some movement happen?
え？後ろ、大変じゃない？
Huh? Behind us, isn't it crazy?
あ、なんか画面が、画面が、やばい、みんな、やばい、後ろ見て、後ろ見て、後ろ見て！
Ah, the screen, the screen, oh no, everyone, oh no, look behind, look behind, look behind!
はにゃ~~~ん! 忘れちゃったのかなにゃん?
Hannya~~~! Did you forget, nya?
あたちが、ホワイトブリニャンだにゃ~~~~ん!!!
I am White Burinyan~~~~!!!
推しピのスマイルまで何マイル~~~!!?
How many miles to my oshi-pi's smile~~~!!?
世界の果てまで狂わせて~~~~!!
Drive me crazy to the ends of the earth~~~~!!
こっち向いて ピッピッピッ
Look this way, pi-pi-pi
ハート作って ピッピッピッ
Make a heart, pi-pi-pi
あんたが大将 ピッピッピッ
You're the general, pi-pi-pi
神様助けて また恋をしました
God help me, I fell in love again
次こそは本当のマジのラブなんだから
This time it's truly serious love
合鍵ちょーだい ピッピッピッ
Give me a spare key, pi-pi-pi
香水嗅がせて ピッピッピッ
Let me smell your perfume, pi-pi-pi
三秒見つめて ピッピッピッ
Stare at me for three seconds, pi-pi-pi
にゃーーーん♡
Nyaaaaan♡
はにゃ~~ん! 忘れちゃったのかにゃん?
Hanya~~n! Did you forget, nya?
あ・た・ち・が ホワイトブリニャンだにゃ~~~~ん!
It's me, White Brinyan~~~~!
推しピのスマイルまで 何マイル~~~~!~!?
How many miles to my oshi-pi's smile~!?
世界の果てぇまで狂わせて~~~~!!
Drive the edge of the world wild~~~~!!
メイクも
Makeup,
ネイルも
nails too,
ガチ担当 (きゃぴ♡)
dedicated roles (kyapi♡)
ほら可愛いこセット (にゃにゃにゃにゃにゃん♡)
Look, cute set (nyanyanyanyanyan♡)
ラブラブちゅわわ 貢いじゃう 全部 ♡
Lovestruck chuwawa, I'll give you everything ♡
ここはパラダイス (ハイハイハイハイ！)
This is paradise (Hai-hai-hai-hai!)
ドキドキはわわ なでで されたら
When my heart races and I'm petted,
もっともっと 好きになっちゃう (ちゅわ♡)
I fall more and more in love (chuwa♡)
モエモエシュワワ 煽っちゃダメダメよ ♡
Moe-moe-shuwawa, don't tease me, no no ♡
羽ばた いちゃう から (ハイハイハイハイ！)
Because I'll take flight (Hai-hai-hai-hai!)
アフターケアしてぇん ♡
Give me aftercare ♡
ハートたくさん付けちゃう にゃんにゃん♡
I'll attach lots of hearts, nyanyan ♡
今夜の My Tier 一番 テーブル
Tonight's top table on my tier
ブリにゃんモード 入りましたぁ~~~ん!
Brinyan mode has entered~~~n!
世界で一番 愛 シテル ~ ♡ (わっふー！)
The most in the world, I love you~ ♡ (Wahoo!)
「ぁーーん 会いたかったぁん！ 推しピ~~♡」
"Ahhh, I wanted to see you! Oshi-pi~~♡"
「今日も頑張ってきたよ~ ♡ 褒めて? 褒めて~ん♡」
"I worked hard today too~ ♡ Praise me? Praise me~n♡"
「ねぇ ハブして? ぎゅーって、チューして? チューして?」
"Hey, hug me? Squeeze me, kiss me? Kiss me?"
可愛い可愛い 推しピの為なら 人生まるっとあげちゃいま~~~す ♡
For my cute, cute oshi-pi, I'll give my whole life~~~!
他の子見るとか ありえな~~~い
Looking at other girls is impossible~~~!
もう粗粗は NO,NO 許さな~~~い
No more rough stuff, NO, NO, I won't forgive it~~~!
年がら年中 I won't you
Year-round, I won't you
承認欲求 暴走 中
Attention-seeking running wild
お手製 アクスタ ほっぺに ちゅー
Homemade acrylic stand, kiss on the cheek
ぴえんぱおん の スピリタス~
Spirits of Pien-Paon~
こっち見て？ こっち見て？ 愛情たっぷり ごっつぁん です
Look this way? Look this way? Full of love, feast your eyes!
離れないよ もう 推しピのものだもん ♡
I won't leave you, I'm already oshi-pi's property ♡
だから 今日も 頑張るにゃ ♡
That's why I'll work hard today too, nya ♡
女の子はね 「可愛い」の数だけ 可愛くなるんだにゃ~ん ♡
Girls become cuter by the number of "cute"s ♡
ラブラブちゅわわ 捧げます 全部 ♡
Lovestruck chuwawa, I dedicate everything ♡
ここはパラダイス (ハイハイハイハイ！)
This is paradise (Hai-hai-hai-hai!)
ドキドキはわわ ハグハグ されたら
When my heart races and I'm hugged,
ずっとずっと 好きになっちゃう (ちゅわ♡)
I fall more and more in love (chuwa♡)
あれあれ どうして そっぽ向いちゃう の ? あの子のせいだよね ?
Hey hey, why are you looking away? Is it that girl's fault?
溢れる 恋 模様 ♡ ハートたくさん付けちゃう にゃんにゃん ♡
Overflowing love pattern ♡ I'll attach lots of hearts, nyanyan ♡
愛してる♡ 愛してる♡
I love you ♡ I love you ♡
丘を越えて 山を越えて 谷を越えてゆくんだ
Over hills, over mountains, crossing valleys
川を越えて 海を越えて 空を越えてゆくんだ
Crossing rivers, crossing seas, crossing the sky
雨上がりの空 虹を描いて 皆に会いに行くよ
Drawing a rainbow in the post-rain sky, I'm going to see everyone
大切なのは 僕でいること 間違いだらけの毎日も
What's important is being myself, even in my mistake-filled days
手と手をつないで 目と目を合わせて どこまでも歩こう
Holding hands, locking eyes, let's walk anywhere
おサルさんのロンド キリンさんのロンド
Monkey's rondo, giraffe's rondo
ウサギさんのロンド 気がつけば僕も
Rabbit's rondo, before I knew it, me too
小鳥たちのロンド 子犬たちのロンド
Little birds' rondo, puppies' rondo
子猫たちのロンド 笑顔で歌うよ
Kittens' rondo, singing with a smile
朝を越えて 昼を越えて 夜を越えてゆくんだ
Crossing morning, crossing noon, crossing night
雲を越えて 月を越えて 星を越えてゆくんだ
Crossing clouds, crossing the moon, crossing the stars
星空の下に 浮かべた涙 皆に会いに行くよ
Tears floating under the starry sky, I'm going to see everyone
大人になれば わかるはずなのに 悩み事ばかり増えてゆく
When you become an adult, you should understand, yet worries only increase
そんなときには 空を見上げて 皆と一緒に歌いながら
At times like that, look up at the sky and sing together with everyone
丘を越えて山を越えて
Crossing the hills, crossing the mountains,
谷を越えてゆくんだ
crossing the valleys - here I go!
川を越えて海を越えて
Crossing the rivers, crossing the sea,
空を越えてゆくんだ
crossing the sky - here I go!
雨上がりの空虹を描いて
Spreading the message that after the rain,
皆に会いに行くよ
there's a colorful rainbow!
大切なのは僕でいること
Meeting everyone - here I go!
間違いだらけの毎日も
Hey, don't y'know that it's okay to be yourself?
手と手をつないで目と目を合わせて
Even if you mess up everyday - oh, well!
どこまでも歩こう
Just hold the hand of someone...
八百屋さんのロンド
"Look in their eyes, everyone!"
気が付けば僕も
Now, let's march on and have some fun!
小人さんのロンド
The dwarf is doing the rondo,
巨人さんのロンド
the giant is doing the rondo,
宇宙人のロンド
the aliens do the rondo,
気が付けば僕も
and I, as well, am marching on!
寂しがりのロンド
The lonely are doing the rondo,
忘れん坊のロンド
the forgetful are doing the rondo,
照れ屋さんのロンド
the bashful are doing the rondo,
笑顔で歌うよ
smiling as they sing along!
お母さんのロンド
Mama is doing the rondo,
お父さんのロンド
daddy is doing the rondo,
お姉ちゃんのロンド
and I, as well, am marching on!
気が付けば僕も
Grandma is doing the rondo,
おばあちゃんのロンド
grandpa is doing the rondo,
おじいちゃんのロンド
you and I do the rondo,
君と僕のロンド
and if we sing together,
皆で歌えば
now until forever,
世界は回って笑顔になれるよ
then everyone will smile along!
期待してすぐに諦めて
Expectations built up only to be quickly given up,
曖昧な答えに流されては
drifting along with ambiguous answers.
自分だけ置いて行かれるような
It's a night where such an image—
そんなイメージが胸をつつく夜だ
as if only I am being left behind—
覚えているような覚えていないような
Wandering through memories and longings,
憧れと記憶を彷徨うよ
as if I remember, as if I don't.
僕は君のために 君は僕のために
If I was born for you, and you for me,
生まれたならちょっと嬉しいね
that would make me a little happy.
気付いたら
Before I knew it,
君色に染まってるような
I'm getting dyed in your color.
何気ない言葉で汚して欲しい
I want you to stain me with your casual words.
ずっとわからないフリを続けてきたんだ
I kept pretending I didn't understand all this time,
この時が来るまで
until this moment came.
もしかして 君と釣り合ってないかな
Could it be that I'm not a match for you?
そんな不安もたまに過るけれど
Such anxieties occasionally cross my mind, but
いつも困らせてばかりでごめんね
I'm sorry for always leaving you troubled.
好きだよ 好きだよ
I like you, I like you,
好きだよって伝えたい
I like you! I want to tell you.
傷付けないように言葉を探しても
Even when searching for words so as not to hurt you,
空回り 気持ちに急かされて
my efforts spin uselessly, hurried by my feelings.
ねぇ間違ってるような
Hey, is it like I'm mistaken,
これで合ってるような
or is this right?
二人の答え ずっとよろしくね
Our shared answer—please keep treating me well.
気付いたら
Before I knew it,
君色に染まってるような
I'm getting dyed in your color.
何気ない言葉で汚して欲しい
I want you to stain me with your casual words.
ずっとわからないフリを続けてきたんだ
I kept pretending I didn't understand all this time,
この時が来るまで
until this moment came.
もしかして 君と釣り合ってないかな
Could it be that I'm not a match for you?
そんな不安もたまに過るけれど
Such anxieties occasionally cross my mind, but
いつも困らせてばかりでごめんね
I'm sorry for always leaving you troubled.
好きだよ 好きだよ
I like you, I like you,
好きだよって伝えたい
I like you! I want to tell you.
好きだよ 好きだよ
I like you, I like you,
好きだよって伝えたい
I like you! I want to tell you.
めっちゃ楽しかったね
That was so much fun!
あれ 白髪みそら歌ってないのか 気づいたらさ
Huh? Did Shirakami Sora not sing? Before I knew it,
アキちゃんがさ ドレミファロンド歌っててさ
Aki-chan, you were singing "Doremifa Rondo", and...
白髪みそらは何をしていたんだろうか
what was Shirakami Sora doing the whole time?
いやーそれはね 何に酔ってたんだろうか
Well, you know... what were you getting lost in?
大人たちに聞いてみてね 大人って
Try asking the adults... adults...
いうことで 大人なーにね
...so, adults are like that, huh.
ということで あの 台本にはブリニアモダピピピのPって書いてあるんですけど
So, um, in the script it says "Burinia Modapipipi's P",
歌ったかな?
but did we sing it?
歌ったの? 白髪みは。
Did you sing it, Shirakami?
いや アキロゼは 踊ったよ!
No, Akirose, I danced!
踊ったよ!
I danced!
踊ったの? 踊ったの!
You danced? I danced!
えー なんか記憶があるようなないような なんか白髪みがプリンセスだと思ったのに なんか
Ehh, I kind of remember it, and kind of don't. I thought Shirakami was the princess, but somehow...
別の日姫に奪われていた!
she got snatched away by another princess!
日姫 日姫ってこと?
Princess, you mean princess?
そんな おかしいよ
That's so weird.
まあまあ 元気出すよ
Well, well, cheer up.
うん 元気出す でも アキちゃんとの黄緑色に染まるまでに復活できてよかった!
Yeah, I'll cheer up. But I'm glad I recovered before turning into Aki-chan's yellowish-green!
あ よかった おかえりおおかえり 歌ってよかった
Ah, I'm glad. Welcome back, welcome back. I'm glad we sang.
えへへ
Ehehe.
まあまあまあということでね ドレミファロンド歌っていただいたんですけど
Well, anyway, so yes, we sang Doremifa Rondo,
いやでもちょっと このね 6周年だし ちょっと思い出もあり選ばせてもらった曲なんだけど
and you know, since it's the 6th anniversary, we chose this song with a lot of memories.
あ そうなんだ
Oh, is that right?
そう あの まあロンドでね 一歩ずつこう歩んでいくみたいなところが まあマイペースでね アキロゼは君活動してるんだけど
Yeah. So, like, walking step by step in a rondo... Akirose does activities at her own pace,
みんなもね マイペースでもいいんだよ みたいなそんなメッセージを込めてね 歌わせていただきました
but you guys can go at your own pace too, sending that kind of message, we sang it.
エモすぎる!
That's too emotional!
エモすぎる これからもついていくんでね ついてきてみんなでいこうね ぴっぴっぴっぴっぴっぴっぴってかんじやん
Too emotional. We'll keep following you from now on. Let's all go together. Pipipipipipippi, right?
で そしてね 黄緑色に染まるわ これね白髪みがあの 提案したんだよね アキちゃんね
And then, turning yellowish-green, Shirakami, you proposed this, right, Aki-chan?
そうそうそう そう なんかいいなと思って 可愛いキューンソングで 今回なんかちょっとお姫様にいいかなみたいな
Yeah, exactly. Yeah, I thought it'd be nice, a cute tune song, and this time it'd be good for a princess-like mood.
ね そう 好きだよって言ってた え とおい
Right? Yeah, when I said "I like you", it's far.
いや とっても 可愛いカップル
No, such a cute couple.
よかったですね 皆さん ね ありがとうございます
I'm glad for you guys. Thank you very much.
ね コメントでサザエって言われてるよ
Hey, people in the comments are calling it "Sazae".
サザエさんってみんな違う! みんなファミリーになろうよ じゃ
Sazae-san? Everyone's wrong! Let's all become a family, then.
家族になればいいよ
It's fine if we become family.
まあ それはそれでいいかも ずれないね
Well, that might be fine too. Never changes, huh.
おっと ということで まあせっかくなんでね ちょっと撮影もね したいなと思ってまして ね このお城バックにちょっと二人で
Anyway, since we have the chance, we'd like to take some photos too. With this castle in the background, the two of us...
しかもねブルーじゃーニーズですしね
Plus, it's Blue Journey too.
そうそうそう ということで じゃあちょっと可愛い写真を撮りましょうか
So, let's take some cute photos.
写真で イエーイ イエーイ
With photos, yay, yay!
どうかな? イエーイ ぴぴきゅーん
How is it? Yay, pipikyūn.
きゅんきゅんきゅんきゅん 皆さん撮ってますか 染めてくれるかな?
Kyunkyunkyunkyun. Are you guys taking pictures? Will you dye us?
あ 染めてくれるかな? 難しいな なんか黄緑に染まるよ どうかな? あとなんかポーズないかな?
Ah, will you dye us? It's hard, somehow dyeing into yellowish-green. How is it? Are there any other poses?
みんな ポーズもいいかないや もうなんかもう全て持ってかれて
Everyone, any good poses? No, wait, everything's been taken away.
白髪みのその曲 持ってかれて 記憶がねツツウラウラで
Shirakami's song got taken away. Memories are all over the place.
じゃ これこうしよっく これあいね あ なんか手手は?
Well then, let's do this. This is "Ai". Ah, what about hands?
どっちを選ぶみたいな そういう 君はどっちを選ぶんだい?
Which one will you choose? Which one will you choose?
どっちを選ぶんだい? どっちも持っている
Which one will you choose? I have both.
贅沢ものね 二人とも贅沢ものね
You're greedy. Both of you are greedy.
ハート ハート こ こう こう これ やっぱこれになるよね これになっちゃうね
Heart. Heart. L-like this. Like this. This. It always ends up like this. It really does.
いや もう可愛いの本当にとれた? これで大丈夫ですか?
Man, did we really get cute ones? Is this okay?
逆バージョンもやった ほら
We did the reverse version too, look.
白髪みはこうやって あきちゃんは
Shirakami like this, Aki-chan like this.
カナジイ カナジイ
So sad. So sad.
これがやはり正解なのかも知れない 正解なのかもな 伝統芸能か
This might actually be the correct answer. Might be the correct answer. Traditional performing arts, huh.
ね あ ということで はいみな撮ってくれましたかね 撮った方もぜひぜひいっぱい詰め寄ってください
Right. So, did everyone take pictures? Those who did, please come closer.
いっぱい盛り上げてくれると嬉しいです それでは次は え 4人でまた歌う曲となっておりますので ちょっと向こうの後ろに
I'd be happy if you hype it up a lot. Next up, we have another song for the four of us, so let's head over to the back over there...
行って 引こうかと思いまーす!
...go and retreat, I think!
みんなで後ろに レッツゴー!
Everyone to the back, let's go!
わーい! 帰ろう 帰ろう 次何だっけかな?
Yay! Let's go back. What was next again?
FEVER!!
おいで!おいで! 誘惑のDance again
Come on in! Come on in! Won’t you dance with me again?
おいでよ おいで! 輝夜の城へ
Leave behind the things you fear - Kaguya’s castle is near
出逢いが彩る ミステリー
An evening here will end in a mystery,
危険なペルソナ (助けて~)
A dangerous persona (Help me~)
踊ろう!踊ろう! 終わらないDance beat
Come and dance! Come and dance, to this beat that never ends!
踊ろうよ 踊ろう! 輝夜の城で
Join in if you know the steps, at Kaguya’s castle dance
夜空を切りとる レーザービーム
The lights up in the sky are like laser beams,
私と見てよ? (にゃー?)
So won’t you stay and watch with me? (Meow?)
まばゆい星が照らす想い
Starlight shines upon these feelings, still so strange and new
今宵の夢よ 永遠に
Unknown but ever-growing, my love for you
明日のことは忘れたいのに (にこ~)
My sweet dream, don’t leave me (Smile~)
私は赤い薔薇の姫よ
I’m the princess of roses, this moment’s scarlet toned
今宵の夢よ永遠に
May tonight's dream last forever
明日のことは忘れたいの
I want to forget about tomorrow.
私は紅い 薔薇の姫よ
I am the princess of crimson roses,
優しくさらわれたい
wanting to be gently swept away.
そっと囁いて
Whisper softly to me,
意味ありげに目をそらす
and look away with a meaningful gaze.
あなたは白い 月の騎士
You are the knight of the white moon.
触れた手がまだ熱い
The hand that touched me is still warm,
のがさずに抱きしめて
hold me tight without letting go.
この奇跡を 恋と呼ぶのね
So this miracle is what we call love.
おいで おいで 情熱でダンスゲン おいでよ おいで かぐやの白へ
Come on, come on, dance with passion! Come on, to Kaguya's white realm!
迷い込む アンナンシー
Straying into the labyrinth...
でも愛の 場所ねぇ
Yet, where is love?
踊ろう 踊ろう 止まらない遊び おいでよ おいで かぐやの白で
Let's dance, let's dance in endless play! Come on, in Kaguya's white realm!
静寂が織りなす ピカピカは
The sparkling weave of silence...
私を 待ってて
Wait for me.
きらめく星に誓う心 儚い夢でいいわ
A heart swearing to the glittering stars, a fleeting dream is fine.
明日は明日の風が吹くの
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow.
私は 黒い 薔薇の姫よ
I am the princess of black roses,
激しくさらわれたい
wanting to be fiercely swept away.
だから微笑んで
So smile at me,
追いかけてと目が誘う
my eyes inviting you to chase me.
あなたも 黒い 月の騎士
You are also the knight of the black moon.
瞳の奥は熱い
The depths of your eyes are burning,
つかまえて抱きしめて
catch me and hold me tight.
この奇跡を 恋と呼ぶのね
So this miracle is what we call love.
一緒にいよ 気づいてよ
Be with me, notice it!
他の人を見ないでよ 私だけを見て
Don't look at anyone else, look only at me!
後悔するわよ
You'll regret it.
楽しもう 早くしなさいよ
Let's have fun, hurry up!
気づいたのですか? いいの?
Did you realize? Is that okay?
私は 赤い 薔薇の姫よ
I am the princess of crimson roses,
優しくさらわれたい
wanting to be gently swept away.
そっと囁いて
Whisper softly to me,
意味ありげに目をそらす
and look away with a meaningful gaze.
あなたは 白い 月の騎士
You are the knight of the white moon.
触れた手がまだ熱い
The hand that touched me is still warm,
のがさずに抱きしめて
hold me tight without letting go.
この奇跡を 恋と呼ぶのね
So this miracle is what we call love.
君を泣かすから だから一緒には居れないな
Because I'll make you cry, that's why we can't be together.
君を泣かすから 早く忘れて欲しいんだ
Because I'll make you cry, I want you to forget me quickly.
人間だからね たまには違うものも食べたいね
We're human, after all, so sometimes we want to eat something different.
君を泣かすから そう君を泣かすから
Because I'll make you cry, yes, because I'll make you cry.
でも味気ないんだよね 会いたいなんだよね
Yet it's so bland... I want to see you.
大体曖昧なんだよね 愛の存在証明なんて
It's all so vague, like proof that love exists.
君が教えてくれないから
Since you won't teach me.
何十回の夜を過ごしたって得られぬような愛してるを並べてみて
Try lining up "I love you"s that you could never get even spending tens of nights...
何十回の夜を過ごしたって得られぬような最高のフルコースを頂戴
Give me the ultimate full course meal that you could never get even spending tens of nights!
君を泣かすから きっと一生は...
Because I'll make you cry, surely a lifetime...
君を泣かすから
Because I'll make you cry,
きっと一生は無理だよね
being together forever is surely impossible, right?
君を泣かすから
Because I'll make you cry,
胸がとても痛くなんだ
my chest aches so much.
人間だからね
We're only human, after all,
たまには分かり合えなくなって
so sometimes we can't understand each other.
君を泣かすから
Because I'll make you cry,
また君を泣かすから
I'll make you cry again.
でも自信がないんだよね
But I have no confidence,
変わりたくないんだよね
I don't want to change,
君以外会いたくないんだよね
I don't want to see anyone but you.
なんて勝手だね
How selfish of me.
大体曖昧だったよね
It was mostly vague, wasn't it?
愛の存在証明なんて
Proof that love exists...
君がそこに居るのにね
even though you are right there.
何百回の夜を過ごしたって得られぬような
Spending hundreds of nights, yet never finding such love,
愛してるを並べてみて
trying to string together "I love you"s—
何百回の夜を過ごしたって得られぬような最高のフルコースを頂戴
give me the finest full-course meal that hundreds of nights could never buy!
最高のフルコースを頂戴
Give me the finest full-course meal!
離れないで傍に居てくれたのは
The one who stayed by my side and didn't leave
結局君ひとりだったよね
in the end, was just you, wasn't it?
涙のスパイスは君の胸に残ってしまうだろうけど
The spice of tears will probably remain in your heart, but—
何千回の夜を過ごしたって得られぬような
Spending thousands of nights, yet never finding such love,
愛してるを並べるから
I will string together "I love you"s, so—
何千回の夜を過ごしたって得られぬような最高のフルコースを頂戴
give me the finest full-course meal that thousands of nights could never buy!
何万回の夜を過ごしたって忘れぬような
Spending tens of thousands of nights, yet never forgetting such love,
愛してるを並べるから
I will string together "I love you"s, so—
何万回の夜を過ごしたって忘れぬような最高のフルコースを頂戴
give me the finest full-course meal that tens of thousands of nights could never make us forget!
世界で一番おひめさま
I'm the world's number one princess,
そういう扱い心得てよね
so make sure you know how to treat me!
その一 いつもと違う髪型に気付くこと
Rule one: notice when my hairstyle is different,
その二 ちゃんと靴まで見ること
Rule two: look closely down to my shoes,
いいね?
okay?
その一 いつもと違う髪型に気付くこと
Rule one: notice when my hairstyle is different,
その二 ちゃんと靴まで見ること
Rule two: look closely down to my shoes,
その三 ワタシの一言には三つの言葉で返事すること
Rule three: reply to every word I say with three words,
わかったら右手をお留守なのをなんとかして!
so if you understand, do something about my empty right hand!
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything—
キミに心から思って欲しいの
I just want you to truly feel from your heart
かわいいって
that I'm cute!
世界で一番おひめさま 気付いて ねぇねぇ
World's number one princess—notice me, hey hey!
待たせるなんて論外よ ワタシを誰だと思ってるの?
Making me wait is out of the question! Who do you think I am?
もう なんだか あまいものが食べたい!
I want something sweet right now!
欠点? かわいいの間違いでしょ?
Flaws? You mean adorable mistakes, right?
文句は許しませんの
Complaints are not allowed!
あのね? ワタシの話ちゃんと聞いてる? ちょっとぉ…
Hey, are you listening to what I'm saying? Hey...
あ、それとね? 白いうおうまさん決まってるでしょ?
Oh, and also! A white horse is a given, right?
迎えに来て わかったらかしずいて手を取って「おひめさま」って
Come pick me up! Kneel down, take my hand, and say "My princess!"
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything—
でもね 稍微叱ってくれたっていいのよ?
but you know, it's okay to scold me just a little bit, right?
世界でワタシだけのおうじさま 気付いてほらほらおててが空いてます
The prince who belongs only to me in this world—notice how my hands are empty!
無口で無愛想なおうじさま もうどうして!
You silent, unfriendly prince, why must you be like this?!
気付いてよ 早く みんなみんな我慢します...
Hurry up and notice! Everyone is holding back...
わがままな子だと思わないで あとで後悔するわよ
Don't think of me as a selfish brat, you'll regret it later!
当然です! だってワタシは世界で一番おひめさま
Of course! Because I'm the world's number one princess!
ちゃんと見ててよね どこかに行っちゃうよ?
Watch me properly, or I'll go somewhere else!
世界で一番おひめさま ちゃんと見ててよね どこかに行っちゃうよ?
World's number one princess—watch me properly, or I'll go somewhere else!
ふいに抱きしめられた 急にそんなぁ?
Suddenly hugged from behind—suddenly like that?
“轢かれる 危ないよ” そう言ってそっぽ向くキミ
"You'll get run over, it's dangerous," you say as you look away.
…こっちが危ないわよ
...You're the dangerous one here!
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world,
そういう扱い心得てよね
treat me accordingly, okay?
その一 いつもと違う髪型に気付くこと
First, notice when my hair is different,
その二 ちゃんと靴までみること いいね?
and second, check my shoes too, got it?
その三 わたしたちの一言には三つの言葉で返事すること
And third, reply to every word with three.
わかったら右手がお留守なのをなんとかして!
Do something about my right hand being empty!
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
I'm not being selfish or anything.
キミに心から思ってほしいの かわいいって
I just want you to truly think I'm cute.
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world,
気がついて ねぇねぇ
so pay attention, hey, hey!
待たせるなんて論外よ
Making me wait is out of the question.
わたしを誰だと思ってるの?
Who do you think I am?
もうなんだか あまいものが食べたい!
I want something sweet right now!
いますぐによ
Go get it immediately.
ケッテン? かわいいの間違いでしょう
Fault? Surely you mean charm, right?
文句は許しませんの
Complaints will not be tolerated.
あのね 私の話ちゃんと聞いてる?
Hey, are you even listening to me?
ちょっ…
Wait...
あい、それとね 白いおうさま 決まってるでしょ?
Oh, and you know, a white horse, obviously,
迎えに来て
come and take me away.
わかったらかしずいて 手をそっと「おひめさま」って
Take my hand and call me "princess".
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
I'm not saying I'm being selfish,
でもね 少しぐらい叱ってくれたっていいのよ?
but you could scold me a little, you know?
世界でわたしだけのおうさま
My very own prince in the world,
気がついて ほらほら
realize that, look, look,
おててが空いています
our hands are empty.
無口で不愛想なおうさま
A reticent and blunt prince,
もうどうして! 気づいてよ早く
why won't you notice already?
絶対きみはわかってない!
You definitely don't get it at all!
わかってないわ…
You really don't get it...
さよならプリンセス 宙に舞っている
Goodbye, Princess, dancing in space.
眠り沈むその姿は華やかな
That sleeping figure is so glamorous.
魅惑のハッピーエンド
An enchanting happy ending,
私とさよならだ
it's goodbye to you and me.
鏡の中 独り縛られて
Bound alone inside the mirror,
頭の中 逃げ回る毎日です
every day escapes inside my head.
ずっと ずっと
Always, always...
だって私変われないし
Because I can't change,
夢もないし口もないし
have no dreams, no words,
つまらないし可愛くないし
boring, not even cute,
わからないし仕方ないし
I don't understand, can't be helped.
意図せず気づいたらまるで
Unknowingly, before I knew it,
指環が首環になっていたんだ
my ring had turned into a collar.
壊れた大人の愛情なんだ
This is the love of broken adults.
期待を踏蹴った私のことなんて気にしないでね
Don't worry about my kicked expectations.
さよならプリンセス 宙に舞っている
Goodbye, Princess, dancing in space.
独り浮かぶその姿は華やかな
That figure floating alone is glamorous.
魅惑のハッピーエンド
An enchanting happy ending,
私とさよならだ
it's goodbye to you and me.
間抜けなプリンセス 過去とバイバイだ
Clumsy princess, goodbye to the past.
この際何も全てを燃やしてしまおう
Let's burn everything away this time.
このまま宙を泳いで あの星になれたら
If I could swim through space and become a star,
私、私とさよならだ
it's goodbye to me and you.
心の穴 悶え疼いた身体の中
Inside a body where the void aches,
空回る毎日です
every day spins round and round.
ずっと ずっと
Always, always...
だってあなた頭いいし 変わらないし 足長いし
Because you're smart, unchanging, tall,
面白いし顔も可愛いし さりげないし 仕方ないし
funny, cute face, casual, inevitable,
溢れるオーラはまるで
that overflowing aura is like
キラキラ輝くアンチテーゼ
a sparkling antithesis.
メロメロ私は面目ないね
I'm head over heels, no dignity.
古い昨日の私のことなんて探さないでね
Don't look for my old self.
さよならプリンセス 愛に酔っている
Goodbye, Princess, intoxicated by love.
独り揺るぐその姿は鮮やかな
That swaying figure is so vivid.
理想のハッピーエンド
An ideal happy ending,
私とさよならだ
it's goodbye to you and me.
さよならプリンセス 全てバイバイだ
Goodbye, Princess, everything is goodbye.
巡り巡る幸せに絡まるほど
Entangled in the circulating happiness,
間抜けなハッピーエンド
a clumsy happy ending,
可愛くなれたかな
did I become cute?
私、私はすでに分かっていたんだ
I, I already knew it all along,
この世とさよならか?
is this world a goodbye?
はい、ちょっとね、な、6年目じゃないか？
Right, well, isn't it the, like, 6th year?
え、今は6年目...あ、今6年目...
Uh, right now it's the 6th year... Ah, right now it's the 6th year...
あ、今6年目を迎えたんですけど...
Ah, we've reached our 6th year, but...
ちょっとね、ま、まずね、原点に戻り...
well, first off, let's go back to our roots...
ちょっと、まあ、あの頃のガツン系した感じにね、戻って...
and go back to that intense style from back then...
ちょっと写真を見返そうということでね！
and reminisce by looking at old photos!
めちゃくちゃ可愛かった！そう、そういうわけよ！
They were so cute! Yeah, exactly!
めっちゃ可愛かった、ハートちゃんって感じだった！
They were so cute, like total heart-eyes!
ちゃんと見てくれてさー！
And they were really looking at us!
この歌声は...！すんなり要素が急にね...！
This singing voice...! The smooth element suddenly...!?
急にじゃなくて取って付けたような！急にじゃなくて、そうさね、2人でね、そう、
Not suddenly, like it was tacked on! Not suddenly, yeah, we two did it, yeah,
セレパルシヴァイオレットよ！そう、これはね、やっぱお姫様っていうタイトルですから！
Celepal Violet! Yeah, because the title is "Princess"!
そう、プリンセスって付いてる...そう、プリンセスって付いてるからね、すごいちょっと安直...なんだけど...
Yeah, since "Princess" is attached... yeah, since "Princess" is in the title, it's a bit straightforward... but...
でもさ、やっぱ可愛い系のさ、曲で...
But you know, for cute-style songs,
なんかちょっとこうポップな感じでね、そうそうそう、なんかポップ担当と可愛い担当って感じなんだよね、ぴったりだったかなと、思いますね！
like with a pop feel, right, right, it felt like a pop lead and a cute lead, so it was a really good fit, I think!
千曲でしたね！ちなみにこのペアはね...あの...
It was a thousand songs! By the way, this pair... um...
あ、グーチョキパー、グーチョキパーじゃないよ、グートパーで！
Ah, Rock-paper-scissors—no, not rock-paper-scissors, Gu-to-pa!
グートパーで、合わせ...みたいな感じで、やりましたね！
Gu-to-pa, matching... like that, we did it!
それ、それはさ、今言わなくていいじゃん！忘れとハートちゃんペアと、向こうになるよ！
You didn't need to say that right now! Forgotten Haato-chan pair and the other one!
あ、そっか、仲良くて、やったってことにしとくじゃん！もういいじゃん！
Ah, right, let's just say we got along well and did it! That's fine!
なんで、なんで、ごめん！仲良しですからね、やりました！そういうわけですね！はい！
Why, why, sorry! We're good friends, so we did it! That's how it is! Yes!
はい、というわけで、あの2人もやってたんだけど...
Yes, so, those two were doing it too, but...
撮影会をちょっとね、やりたくない？え、あ、やりたい、やりたい！
wouldn't you want to do a photoshoot session? Uh, ah, we want to, we want to!
いや、でもさ、ほら、あれは鉄、鉄板じゃん？
No, but look, that's a classic, right?
え、何々？鉄板だって！
Eh, what's what? A classic!
また間違えた！
I messed up again!
あれ家具やってるんだよ！
We're doing furniture!
そうそうそう、家具や...でもなんか鉄、鉄、鉄って言ってて、家具やね！
Right right, furniture... but you kept saying iron, iron, iron, furniture, right!
そう、ほら、戻ってよってのをおしゃれにしたいだとか、そうね、家具やもめっちゃ良かったですね！
Right, see, wanting to make "let's go back" stylish, right, the furniture shop was also really great.
あの、何セレパータだっけ？あ、そう、セレパータがあったからみんなのね、セレパータがもう本当に個性が被ってました！
Um, what was it, Sereparta? Ah, right, since there was Sereparta, everyone's Sereparta really overlapped in personality!
あ、アキロゼのセクシーさ際立ってたね！
Ah, Akirose's sexiness stood out!
エロかったね！エロかった、エロいとか言っちゃダメだよ公式で！
It was erotic! It was erotic, you shouldn't say "erotic" officially!
ということで、撮影会ちょっと、ポーズは...ハートちゃん、みんな何が欲しいの？ハートポーズいったいとく？
So, for the photoshoot session, poses... Haato-chan, what does everyone want? Heart pose, shall we do that?
え、二人柄はこれだったけど、ちゃんと...
Eh, the two of us were like this, but properly...
リハでさ、ちゃんとやったよ！リハで、押さないで！
In rehearsal, we did it properly! In rehearsal, don't push!
はい、ちゃんとやって、ちゃんと言って...ハート！ちょっと割れてる...
Yes, do it properly, and say... Heart! It's a bit broken...
ねえ、な、ねえ、なんで！
Hey, Na, hey, why!?
ねえ、ほか何する？他は、まつりちゃんはまつりちゃん、まつりちゃん、まつりポーズ！
Hey, what else? What else, Matsuri-chan is Matsuri-chan, Matsuri-chan, Matsuri pose!
まつりポーズってなに？こんな感じ？あ、そう、いいじゃん！こっちがいい？こっちがいい？どっちがいいよ？
What's a Matsuri pose? Like this? Ah, yeah, that's good! Is this better? Is that better? Which is better?
どっちもいーじゃん！いーじゃん！
Both are good! Good!
え、せっかくさ、センターだしたほら、なんかこうお城がさ、いい感じに見える
Eh, since we went out of our way to be center, look, the castle looks really nice,
プリンセスっぽい感じに...プリンセスっぽい感じに行くよ！
like a princess... let's go with a princess-like feel!
ポーズ！あ、じゃあわかった、間に王子様が入るとね？
Pose! Ah, then I know, if a prince comes between us, right?
あ、そうそうそうそう、どっちを選びますか？王子、どっちを選ぶの？
Ah, right right right, which one will you choose? Prince, which one will you choose?
ホールームちゃんこれ、そうだよ、めっっちゃいい、めっっちゃいい！
Haorumu-chan this, that's right, super good, super good!
ツイートしてね、このタグで！え、待って、ほら、結んだ！
Tweet with this tag! Eh, wait, look, we tied it!
結んだ！これ馬鹿、馬鹿、馬鹿、ちょっと！次行くぞ、次行くぞ！
Tied it! You're an idiot, idiot, idiot, wait! Let's go to the next one, next one!
はい、次行きましょうね！そう、そう、そうということで戻りましたね！
Yes, let's go to the next one! Right, right, so we're back!
はい、次、次も頑張って盛り上がっていきましょう！すいません、みなさん、連れてくんで！
Yes, next, let's work hard and get hyped for the next one too! Sorry everyone, we're taking you along!
すみません、連れてって、もう、すんごいヤッちゃった！
Sorry, leading you, man, we totally messed up!
輝く夜空 四季巡って
Shining night sky, the four seasons revolve
春風 君を乗せて
Spring breeze carrying you
夏色が迎えるよ
Summer colors welcome you
色めく秋が背中を押したなら
If colorful autumn pushes your back
もふもふ吹雪 キラメキ
Fluffy blizzard, sparkling
めぐりめぐりハート
Revolving, revolving hearts
なんにもわからない 一歩進んで
Taking a step forward with no clue
やっと ここまでたどり着けたね
We've finally made it this far
待ちわびてる (ずーっと)
Waiting anxiously (the whole time)
素敵なステージ
A wonderful stage
一番に絶対 見せてあげるよ！ (おー！)
I'll definitely show you the best! (Oh!)
行こうよ smile ! smile ! catch up , future !
Let's go, smile! smile! catch up, future!
無邪気に巡る季節が世界を
Seasons revolving innocently around the world
輝く夜空巡って
In the twinkling night sky, the seasons turn,
春風君を乗せて夏色が迎えるよ
the spring breeze carries you as summer welcomes you.
色めく秋が背中を押したら
When the colorful autumn gives you a push,
もふもふ吹雪キラメキ
fluffy blizzards and sparkles.
めぐりめぐりハート
Turning and turning heart,
なにもわからない一歩進んで
taking a step forward knowing nothing at all,
やっとここまでにたどり着けんだ
we've finally made it all the way here.
待ちわびてる(ずっと!)
Waiting so eagerly (Always!)
素敵なステージ
for a wonderful stage—
一番に絶対見せてあげるよ! (おー!)
we'll be sure to show you first! (Oh!)
行こう！smile! smile! catch up, future!
Let's go! Smile! Smile! Catch up, future!
無敵に巡る季節が
The invincible seasons keep turning,
世界を駆け巡って夢のような日々へと
running around the world into dream-like days.
光れ！bright! bright! light up, future!
Shine! Bright! Bright! Light up, future!
僕らが一等星！
We are the first-magnitude stars!
そうさ！照らし続けよう
That's right! Let's keep shining on!
真っ白な気持ち
Pure white feelings,
12時の鐘なんて忘れちゃって
forget about the 12 o'clock bell.
ずっととけない魔法をかけよう
Let's cast a magic that never melts,
ときめいて (そっと)
letting your heart flutter (Quietly).
胸躍る時間を贈るから
Sending you time that makes your heart dance,
絶対ついておいでよ！ (おー！)
so make sure you follow us! (Oh!)
届け spark! spark! pop-up, future!
Reach! Spark! Spark! Pop-up, future!
いまを駆ける五つ星
Five stars running through the present,
世界も巻き込んで賑やかに遊ぼう
involving the whole world, let's play lively!
ずっと flash! flash! make up, future!
Always Flash! Flash! Make up, future!
目も眩むシチュエーション
A dazzling situation,
まだ踊り足りないでしょ？
aren't you still not tired of dancing?
カーテンコールのずっとずっと先まで
All the way far beyond the curtain call,
楽しむ気持ちさえ持って来たら
if you bring your feeling of enjoyment,
きっと誰でも主役になれるよ
surely anyone can become the protagonist.
羽も尻尾も笑顔もさらけ出して
Exposing your wings, tails, and smiles,
もっと step! (step!)
more step! (Step!)
もっと jump! (jump!)
more jump! (Jump!)
またとないこの世界を
let's play this one-of-a-kind world
一緒に遊び尽くそう！ (おー！)
to the fullest together! (Oh!)
響け clap! clap! let's sing, future!
Resonate! Clap! Clap! Let's sing, future!
このメロディが終わっても
Even if this melody ends,
決して今日だけの思い出にはしないよ
we will never make it just a memory of today.
行こう！smile! smile! catch up, future!
Let's go! Smile! Smile! Catch up, future!
無敵に巡る季節が
The invincible seasons keep turning,
世界を駆け巡って夢のような日々へと
running around the world into dream-like days.
光れ！bright! bright! light up, future!
Shine! Bright! Bright! Light up, future!
僕らが一等星！
We are the first-magnitude stars!
そうさ！照らし続けよう
That's right! Let's keep shining on!
スポットライトは終わらない
The spotlight will never end.
響け clap! clap! let's sing, future!
Resonate! Clap! Clap! Let's sing, future!
このメロディが終わっても
Even if this melody ends,
決して今日だけの思い出にはしないよ
we will never make it just a memory of today.
行こう！smile! smile! catch up, future!
Let's go! Smile! Smile! Catch up, future!
無敵に巡る季節が
The invincible seasons keep turning,
世界を駆け巡って夢のような日々へと
running around the world into dream-like days.
光れ！bright! bright! light up, future!
Shine! Bright! Bright! Light up, future!
僕らが一等星！
We are the first-magnitude stars!
そうさ！照らし続けよう
That's right! Let's keep shining on!
スポットライトは終わらない
The spotlight will never end.
はーい、というわけで
Hi there, and so...
プラズマジックシーズンズでございました！イエーイ！
that was "Plasmagic Seasons!" Yay!
いやー、あの状態からよく歌って踊れたなもう
Man, how did we manage to sing and dance after that condition?
いや風邪大丈夫？ねえ？めちゃくちゃって、こっち戻ってきたでしょ思ったら、
Hey, is your cold okay? Right? When we thought we came back over here,
びっかびかで切り替え、切り替えが大変だった、ちゃんときが、あれがすごかった
it was flashing and switching was tough, getting dressed properly, that was amazing!
切り替えが本当すごかった、バタバタしてた、バタバタしてたよね、めちゃくちゃびっくりしてました皆さん、
The transition was really amazing, it was so hectic, everyone was super surprised!
いやでもね、プラズマジックシーズンズじゃちょっと久しぶりにね歌って踊りましたの、この曲もね
But you know, we sang and danced to "Plasmagic Seasons" after quite a while, this song too!
いや、相変わらず楽しい楽曲でね、ありがとうございます！
Yeah, it's as fun a song as ever, thank you!
ではね、なんと次が最後の曲になってしまうんですけども、その前に我々からの お知らせをね、お届けしますよ！
Now then, believe it or not, the next song will be our very last one, but before that, we have an announcement from us!
なんと、我々ホロライブ1期生活動6周年の記念、1期生のね、全員のセットのが出ちゃうの、ね、ガチガチでしょガチガチ！
What's more, for the 6th anniversary of hololive 1st generation activities, a complete set for all 1st gen members is coming out! It's super serious, right, super serious!
ホロライブ1期生6周年記念！
Hololive 1st Generation 6th Anniversary!
ということで、ラインナップ見ていきましょう！
So, let's check out the lineup!
こちら！アクリルスタンド (全4種)
Here! Acrylic stands (all 4 types).
こちらですね、ま今回はプリンセスということで、それぞれちょっとね、ドレスをポージングしてる、もう、こうなっててね、こうなっててね、足クロスしてる！
Here, since this time the theme is princesses, everyone is posing in their dresses, like this, with their legs crossed!
プリンセス仕様でのアクリルスタンドをご用意させていただきました！いや、みんな、ちょっと、可愛いよね！
We've prepared acrylic stands in princess specifications! Man, everyone's a bit cute, right?
ちょっと一瞬ライト当たったの
The light just hit me for a second...
あ、気付いた？
Ah, you noticed?
気付いたの？ めちゃくちゃヤバいよね！
You noticed? It's so amazing, right!
ねぇねぇ！ 今日だけならミスってあげ…やめ！やめやめ！
Hey hey! I'll let you make a mistake
just for today—stop, stop stop!
ちょっと見せてみて！
Let me see!
あ、ダメダメ！やっぱ一緒に見て？
Ah, no no! Actually, let's look at it together?
でもさ、まつりちゃんのもさ、ふぉっとしててめっちゃ可愛いよね！
Also, Matsuri-chan's is fluffy
and super cute!
実は意外にね、なんかっていうか、一番露出が少ないのがまつりなんだよね。
Actually, surprisingly, Matsuri
has the least skin exposure.
そうなんだよね！ 意外に露出少ないの？
Is that right? Surprisingly low exposure?
いや、だからそこ可愛いんだけど、やっぱり……
Yeah, that's what makes it cute, but still...
じゃあ、続いていきますか！続いてこちら！
Well then, shall we continue? Next is this!
おぉ！またございます！はい、こちらチェキ風カード＆チェキ風カードホルダーでございます！
Oh! There's more. Yes, here are the
cheki-style cards and cheki card holders!
かっこいい！おしゃれ！
Cool! Stylish!
そう、チェキはね、いろんな人出してると思うんだけど、意外とチェキホルダーがないなっていうのにね、
Right, I think a lot of people put out cheki cards,
but surprisingly there wasn't a cheki holder.
確かに！気づきまして、今回はあわぁチェキと一緒にチェキホルダーをつけさせていただきました！
True! Realizing that, this time we've included
a cheki holder along with the Awawa cheki!
今出てるのが、あわぁのハートジャマ仕様のやつですね。
What's showing now is Awawa's
heart pajama version.
後ろにね、ロゴついてて。ぜひぜひ使ってね、ひそひそお願いします！
It has the logo on the back,
please definitely use it, whispers please.
そしてもう1枚、どうぞ！
And one more, please!
で、どうの？こちら、白上とまつりちゃんですね！
And what about this?
Here are Shirakami and Matsuri-chan!
爽やかで可愛い！
Refreshing and cute.
これもね、またつけてね、まぁ、来年とかにあるか分からないけど、イベントとかね！
You can wear this again, well, I don't know
if there will be one next year, but for events!
いいね、いいね、いいね、いいね、思います！
Nice, nice, nice, nice, I think.
持ち歩けるの嬉しいね！嬉しいですね。そして、そして次！
It's nice to be able to carry it around!
Very happy. And, and next!
これもいいんだよな！
This is also good.
うわぁ、これ！一期生グラスでございます！乾杯！乾杯！
Whoa, this! It's the 1st generation glass!
Cheers, cheers!
これもなかなかおしゃれでね、本当に、素敵なグラスになったなと、思います！
This is also quite stylish, and I think
it turned out to be a really wonderful glass.
記念グッズ感すっごい満載で！
It feels so full of anniversary goods!
東京感たっぷりよ、ね。こちらも愛用していただければと思います！
It's full of Tokyo vibes. Right, right.
I hope you'll cherish this too!
こちらはいつ出るんだ？10時か？このあと10時なのか？このあと10時です？22時にたしか販売開始だったかなと思います！
When does this come out? 10 o'clock? Is it 10 o'clock
after this? I think sales start at 22:00.
よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it!
ま、今回、これで1期生の、ま、まとめての就任グッズが出たのですが、
Well, this time, we released the 1st generation's
combined anniversary goods, but...
まぁ、でも毎年ね、我々なんか個人でも、お、どうして？
Well, every year, we also individually...
Oh, why?
気づいたら……
Before we knew it...
まさか、まさか、そういうことだよ！
No way, no way, that's what it means!
ちょっと話したことなくて。すごいな！そうよね。
We haven't talked about that yet, amazing!
That's right.
あれ好き？好き好き好き、大好き！
Do you like that? Love it, love it, love it, love it!
ということで、はい、こちらです！
And with that, yes, here it is!
赤井はあと活動6周年記念！
Akai Haato's 6th anniversary of activities!
え、我々のですね、周年の個人グッズも、え、明日ですね、リレー配信で販売開始しようと思います！
And so, um, our individual anniversary goods
will also go on sale tomorrow via relay stream!
あ、じゃあこれはコンセプトは何ですか？
Ah, so what is the concept for this?
コンセプトは、やはりはあとまはクッキングチャンネル、かつ可愛いということで、
The concept is, after all, Haatoma is
a cooking channel, plus it's cute,
クッキング×可愛いを掛け合わせました、今回！よろしくお願いします！
so we combined cooking x cute this time!
Please look forward to it!
可愛い！なるほど、可愛いね！
Cute! I see, cute!
こちらは明日の何時かな？えっと19時半から配信します！
What time is this tomorrow?
Um, we're streaming starting at 19:30!
見に来てね！はわん20時です！
Come watch! Hawan is at 20:00!
配信して、そのまた20時から？
We stream, and then starting from 20:00?
はいはい、20時からはこちら！
Yes yes, from 20:00 is this!
ドン！はい、20時からは白組配信させていただきます！
Bam! Yes, starting at 20:00,
Shirakami's stream will take place!
可愛い！ビューティフル！美しい！
Cute! Beautiful!
そう、今回もね、お嬢様な感じに。最近ね、やっとお披露目できた浴衣衣装でグッズを出させていただきます！
Yes, this time too, in a young lady-like style.
We're releasing goods in the yukata outfit!
こちらは20時から配信開始で、そこでね商品を紹介した後、20時30分から、あの、ホロライブのね公式のストアで販売でございますので、よろしくお願いします！
The stream starts at 20:00, and after introducing
the products, it will be sold on Hololive's official store!
お願いしまーす！そして次！
Thank you! And next!
はい、まつりでーす！まつりのコンセプトは、一緒にゲームしよう！って感じでございますね！
Yes, it's Matsuri! Matsuri's concept is
"Let's play games together!"
まつりは20時半に配信スタートで、21時に販売開始なので、よろしくお願いいたします！
Matsuri's stream starts at 20:30, and sales start
at 21:00, so please look forward to it!
コラボちゃんいいよね！いいよ！可愛い！全体可愛い気になるけど、また詳細は明日ということで！
Collab-chan is nice! Good! Cute! I'm curious
about the whole cute look, but more details tomorrow!
はい、そして続いては！はいはいはいはい！
Yes, and next is! Yes yes yes yes!
これもまた可愛い！はい、アキロゼのね、こちらのグッズ。コンセプトは、
This is also cute! Yes, Akirose's goods here. The concept is,
まぁ、普段着というか、いつものね、ちょっとダラしない一面も見せちゃおっかな、みたいな、まぁ、そういう感じのコンセプトになっております！
well, everyday clothes, or rather, showing
a bit of my usual lazy side, something like that!
え、こちらは21時から配信の、21時30分に発売を予定しているので、続けてね、リレー配信をぜひよろしくお願いします！
Um, this streams from 21:00 and is scheduled
to go on sale at 21:30, so please support the relay stream!
お願いしまーす！
Thank you!
実はね、はちゃまの本当の記念なんだよね、そうだよ、そうだよ
Actually, it's Haachama's real anniversary, right? That's right, that's right.
そう、はちゃまは6月2日が記念なのだ是非ともお祝いして下さい
Yes, Haachama's anniversary is June 2nd, so please be sure to celebrate it!
お願いします、夜の19時からね
Please, starting at 7 PM.
また1期生ちょっとラッシュでございますが、よろしくお願いしまーす
We have another 1st Gen rush, so thank you all!
そうそう、ハッシュタグがトレンド入りしている！
That's right, the hashtag is trending!
えー、ありがとー、ありがとう！
Eh, thank you, thank you!
まずはツイートしてね、お祝いツイートしてね
First, tweet about it, tweet your celebrations.
スクショ撮ってね、可愛いところとか
Take screenshots, of cute moments and such.
見せて、あとで見るからね！よろしくお願いしまーす！
Show us, we'll look at them later! Thank you so much!
さて、そしてね、ま、次が最後の楽曲なんですけども
Well then, and next is our final song...
お、何々？何歌おうかな？
Oh, what is it? What should we sing?
ちょっとね、もう一つ告知がございますよね
Hold on, there's another announcement, right?
まあまあまあ、色々ありますよね、告知がこちら！
Well, you know, there are various announcements. Here it is!
パン！来るか？と
Bam! Is it coming?
きたー！やったー！
It's here! Yay!
ホロライブ1期生オリジナル楽曲第2弾が！いよいよ！
Hololive 1st Generation's 2nd original song is finally here!
はい、そのタイトルが「Secret Garden」ということで
Yes, the title is 'Secret Garden'.
なんかさ、かっこいい感じの、ちょっとかっこいい感じがして
It has this cool, slightly cool vibe to it.
白ロビ真っ白だけどもね、真っ白だね
Shirofan's pure white, though it's pure white.
ねえ、こちらの曲をこの後ね、ちょっとお披露目させていただこうかと思いまーす！
Hey, we'd like to premiere this song for you right after this!
はい、楽曲の配信もですね、この後24時から配信開始！
Yes, the song release will also start at midnight right after this!
そしてね、ずっとホロライブの公式チャンネルでねハテナハテナがあったと思うんですけど
And also, I think there were question marks on Hololive's official channel the whole time.
こちらですね、22時15分からこちらの「Secret Garden」のMV公開です！
And here, the MV release for 'Secret Garden' is from 22:15!
これもなんか良い感じにね、本当にになっておりますのでぜひぜひよろしくお願いいたします！
This is also shaping up to be really nice, so please check it out!
ちょっと新曲ってドキドキするね、ドキドキするね
New songs make you nervous, don't they? So nervous.
よし、ということでじゃあ、6周年を締めくくる、ちょっとね、オリ曲やるぞ、やっとか、できるかな？
Alright, with that, let's wrap up our 6th anniversary with our original song. Can we do it?
よっしゃ！6周年、そして7周年も頑張るぞ！おー！
Alright! Let's do our best for the 6th and 7th anniversaries! Oh!
ちょっとみんな立ち位置覚えてるか？まあさすがに何回も練習したから覚えているよ
Do you all remember your positions? Well, we practiced many times so we remember.
最後の曲だ！
It's the final song!
よし、じゃあみんな全部やりいいですか？はい！いきますよー！せーの！Secret Garden！
Alright, is everyone ready? Yes! Here we go! Ready, set! Secret Garden!
月夜のセレナーデ
Serenade of the moonlit night
白い薔薇は誰を想う
Whom does the white rose yearn for?
その身を震わせて
Shivering its body,
愛を歌うの
Singing of love.
零れ落ちた花びらが
The scattered flower petals
寂しさの跡を隠した
Hid the traces of loneliness.
ねえ早く迎えに来て
Hey, come and welcome me soon,
最後のひとひらが落ちるその前に
Before the last petal falls.
今はどんな花とも群れないの
Now, I don't flock with any other flowers,
あなただけを待ってる
Waiting only for you.
あなたとならこの体が壊されたってもう構わない
With you, I wouldn't care even if this body were broken.
棘に触れたら傷つくわ
If you touch the thorns, you'll get hurt.
その覚悟がないならいっそここから消えてよ
If you don't have that resolve, then get lost from here.
重く閉ざした そう Secret Garden
The heavily closed... yes, Secret Garden.
夜風はリゾルート
The night wind is resolute,
白い薔薇は覚醒する
The white rose awakens.
背中押されるように扉開いた
As if pushed from behind, the door opened.
ただ独りで枯れてゆくの？待ってるだけじゃいられない
Will I just wither away alone? I can't just keep waiting.
衝動の赴くまま 茨の道を裸足で駆け抜けてく
Following my impulses, I run barefoot down the thorny path.
凛と咲き誇る華でありたい
I want to be a flower blooming proudly and gracefully,
あなただけを求めて
Seeking only you.
逢いにゆくの どんな遠く離れていても見つけ出せる
I'm going to meet you, no matter how far apart we are, I can find you.
暗い世界も怖くない あなたを感じるから
I'm not afraid of a dark world either, because I feel you.
全て失ったっていい 二度と戻らない そう Secret Garden
It's fine if I lose everything, never to return, yes, Secret Garden.
今は どんな花とも群れないの
Now, I won't flock with any other flowers,
あなただけを求めて
seeking only you.
霞の向こう 私を呼ぶ
Beyond the haze, someone is calling me.
鮮やかに燃える強き薔薇
A strong rose burning vividly.
凛と 咲き誇る華でありたい
I want to be a flower blooming proudly.
やっとここで出逢えた
We finally met here.
あなたとならこの体が
If it's with you, even if this body...
壊されたってもう構わない
...is broken, I don't care anymore.
棘に触れたら傷つくわ
Touching thorns will hurt you.
その覚悟があるのね
Do you have that resolve?
手を取り合えばひろがる
If we hold hands, it spreads outward—
誰も知らない そう
a place nobody knows, yes...
Sacred Universe